From like 11 to 21, I was pretty much
under the influence of alcohol and drugs the entire time.
And by 21 years old,
I was a full-blown heroin addict.
Welcome back to episode 5
of 10 Questions with a Millionaire.
I'm here with Alex Kaufman, a real
estate brokerage owner and real estate investor.
Alex, could you go ahead and give us a brief background
on your history and how you got to where you are today?
So I got started in real estate about
five years ago with my partner, Matt Teipke.
We started off just investing in real estate
together, and then we partnered on the brokerage side.
And we've really grown and
scaled that out here in Texas.
Our goal is to be a
global real estate brokerage for entrepreneurs.
Today, Matt and I together,
we own approximately 100 units together.
And you just mentioned so many like entrepreneurs.
Could you give us them like a brief
background on what it means to be an entrepreneur?
When you get your real estate license,
typically you're taught to just do one thing.
You're taught to just be a listing agent.
You're taught to just do residential.
You're taught.
To just be a buyer's agent.
You're taught to only do commercial, to not do residential,
to not worry about investing in real estate, to not wholesale.
What we call everybody with us here at TRE is entrepreneurs, because we feel that
you should be the true real estate professional and not just limit yourself to one thing.
Because if the market shifts, if you don't know how to do this or that, then
you're going to be limited in how much money you can make and how successful you'll be.
So we teach all of our entrepreneurs how to make money in and
on real estate and how to make money in every aspect of real estate.
What was kind of your career
path to get into real estate?
Sure. I mean, like I could tell the short or the long,
but in short, I was going down the wrong path in high school.
So from like 11 to 21, I was pretty much
under the influence of alcohol and drugs the entire time.
And by 21 years old, I
was a full blown heroin addict.
So I got sober at 21, worked at a firehouse
subs to start my career off making $8.50 an hour.
Then I was washing dishes at a.
Yeah.
Country club and worked in the kitchen.
I worked for oil and gas company and ultimately just knew
that I didn't want a job or to follow a career path.
You know, I always knew that I
could and would make money for myself.
But after I got sober, it was how can
I do it legally and not sell drugs illegally?
And that's when I connected with Matt again.
I've done Matt since I was about eight years
old, and he showed me the path in real estate.
And so how did you get started from your
start in real estate to becoming a real estate broker?
Matt's actually our real estate broker.
But together we own the brokerage.
And so he had his broker license and we said, hey, we want to create a place where people can come and get more out of real estate for themselves
to do the opposite of what I was saying earlier, where the other traditional real estate brokerages put you down this path that you may not want to go down.
At this point, we had been buying real estate together
and we owned, I think, like 15 units at that time.
And then we said, hey, well, let's
create a real estate brokerage for true entrepreneurs.
That's where we started forming
TRE to where it is today.
Yeah.
Right.
That's what I'm saying.
So how quick we went about getting our first
deal from you is path, because you have kilos
and you had tons of money, it's a quick
burn, you went through a little hard to get your
first deal.
So before we really went through any of
these over the months, you figured that we didn't
have have any money.
And what we ended up getting
was a lot of interest in condos.
so you know 28,000 from me and Matt and I
had never bought real estate before but Matt was like
hey man just trust me like there's a good
deal don't worry about it it'll be a great investment
for us down the road ultimately I just placed all
the trust in Matt that he knew what he was doing
and he was looking out for us in this
investment and today that thing's worth easy close to 400,000
wow and we've pulled you know like 150k out of it
too and we still own it and cash flow on the rent
every single month that's that's amazing and how long
has that been since that first deal I think
December 2018 you were in a business partnership with
Matt so how did that come about to being like
hey I want to have you as my partner
and what qualities would you say people should look for
in terms of a business partner we didn't necessarily
start off you know like hey let's partner on this
and everything for the remainder of life right
we just started to do deals together start working
together I was learning from Matt I was doing
some legwork and putting in action for us while he
was doing some of the work that he was doing and
I was doing some of the work that he was doing
and I was doing some of the work that he was doing
you know maybe at his commercial brokerage
or working as property management company just
ultimately trying to find deals and so that's how it
started and it worked out really well I mean we
work really well together we're very similar in a
lot of ways but we're also very different with
our skills and our attributes and what we
enjoy doing and we're also brothers his family's my
family his mom's my mom essentially and then
it also really helped out that we were good
partners on the business side of things I
was talking about this on a podcast yesterday how
just being brothers doesn't necessarily
mean that we would be good
business partners but the fact that we have both
really makes it strong find someone who has the
same values that you do like morally because
if y'all disagree morally and with your values and
where you align spiritually and things like that
you're gonna be in conflict some point moving
forward right make sure that y'all trust each
other make sure that y'all have the same goals
and the same vision and then on the other
side make sure that y'all have different skill sets
like Matt's very good at sales and networking
and meeting people and relationships and ideas and
vision and I'm very good at networking and
meeting people and relationships and ideas and vision and
I really enjoy putting all of that into action I
don't want to go to meetings I want to run our
business and run our operations grow and scale
our operations and so we complement each other
and in those ways what would you say
is your best financial decision and your worst financial
decision you've made in your life I'd say my
best financial decision has been to just put every
single penny that I've made and that we make
into real estate and into our businesses and then the
worst financial decision was to not take
more risks how important is it to take risks
in order to be successful not taking risks is also
a risk even though you may not be putting all
your money up and risking it on this investment you're
taking a risk by not doing that because
you're risking not reaping all the rewards that you're
going to get from the upside there we put
everything on the line at all times and we
just have 110 belief that we're going to make it
work no matter what where do you see yourself in
10 years I don't necessarily have
a and we don't have like a
unit number or financial number of cash flow or
revenue or profit the goal is to have this
Community and network of entrepreneurs under typekey
real estate all across the globe in
the world and all of us be doing deals and
helping each other and growing with each other across the
entire world and then when Elon gets to Mars
we'll be doing it on Mars that's the ultimate
goal is just buy as much real estate as we
can help as many people as we can and continue to
build this tight-knit community of entrepreneurs all
over the world so that everybody can be
helping each other out, growing with each other,
and doing deals together.
For anyone who feels like they're just not doing
what they wanna do right now,
whether it be following their passion,
or they just maybe don't enjoy what they're doing,
what advice would you give to that person?
I think everybody's personal situations are different,
and when I was working at Firehouse Subs,
or one of the other
jobs, I had no responsibility, right?
Just me, like I didn't have
kids, I didn't have a wife,
I didn't have people relying on me,
I just relied on myself.
And so that allowed me to do more things
that maybe somebody else couldn't,
but I just ultimately believe that I think it's hard
to come up with an
excuse for why you can't accomplish
what you wanna do, and I
think that if you want it
bad enough, you'll figure out a way to do it.
And I mean, I sacrificed a lot.
I did not go out and
spend money on this or that,
I did not do things that other people were doing.
I was 100% bought into this way of life,
and making this work, and being successful
in a legal business, that I
gave up a lot of things
that other people were doing.
Ultimately, like in short, just think it's about
sacrificing whatever it is for your dream.
I think that anything is possible,
and anybody can achieve whatever they want to.
I think that the moment we stop allowing people
outside of us, or in our circle, or society,
or whatever it is, to try
and tell us what we can't do,
or what we can do, or
what we need to be, or whatever,
as soon as we let go of that,
and just start being true to ourself,
and 100% accountable to ourself,
I think we can make anything we want reality.
Thank you so much for joining us for episode five
of 10 Questions with a Millionaire.
I'm here with Alex Kaufman.
Where can people find us?
Where can people find out
more about how to reach you,
and how to reach TRE?
Teifke Real Estate, T-E-I-F-K-E.
It's a hard one.
Teifke Real Estate, you can find us on Instagram, YouTube.
Go to our website, Facebook, TikTok,
our headquarters here in Austin, Texas.
Reach out to me.
My phone number's 512-517-1360.
We're here to help, and whatever we can do
to help anybody out.
Awesome, thank you guys so much again for watching.
Please leave a like and subscribe.